# **LAURENT BRUSA**

address Tegner Str. 2 10439 Berlin

cell

email laurentbrusa@me.com stackoverflow.com/multitudes SO portfolio github.com/multitudes/portfolio https://github.com/multitudes url LinkedIn laurentbrusa +49 1522 9623248

### **Profile**

Ideally, I like to write code that is easy to understand, easy to maintain and extend, and in line with the Apple design guidelines.

Between 2021 and 2022, I worked as the sole iOS developer at rooom AG, developing apps with the UIKit or SwiftUI frameworks using the Swift programming language. I was responsible for communicating with Apple through Apple Store Connect, testing and uploading apps to TestFlight, creating apps from design storyboards, adding AR and VR features and updating legacy code.

After leaving room AG, I spent a year travelling, cycling and volunteering in Latin America. Now, I recently started freelancing again, but I am open to new job offers.

I studied as Software Developer in Berlin, and got certified by the IHK, the German Chamber Of Commerce (January 2020). As part of the certification, I did a six months internship in iOS programming. I wrote the project documentation for the exam and held a fifteen-minute presentation in German.

I passed my A-Levels in Electronics and Math in Italy with full marks, and after working in the electronic components industry, I returned to the university in Berlin.

Later in London, I worked in the Apple Travel EMEIA team as a travel consultant providing travel solutions for Apple corporate and retail operations; I collaborated on organising and ticketing travel and accommodation for various events such as the iPhone's and iPad's launch.

#### Skills

Swift and iOS app development, Scrum, Gitlab, Core Data, Cocoa Touch, MVVM, Reactive Programming, MVC, Design Patterns, Continuous Integration (CI)

## Experience

iOS Developer. Freelance. May 2023 - present

rooom AG, Löbstedter Str. 47a, 07749 Jena. February 2021 - April 2022. iOS Developer.

Aerticket, Boppstraße 10, 10967 Berlin October 2016 - September 2017

Chambers Travel, Am Borsigturm 27, 13507 Berlin July 2015 - September 2016 Corporate travel management for different accounts such as GoPro, Epson, Fossil

APPLE Travel, 1 Hanover Street, W1S 1YZ London January 2012 - May 2014 Senior Business Travel Consultant in the BCD travel implant in the Apple HQ

CWT, Global House 424 Bath Rd, UB7 0EB London 2008 - 2011 Senior Business Travel Consultant

ANA, Hythe House 200 Shepherds Bush Rd, W6 7NY London 2007-2008 Air France Marines Dept, Brent House, HA9 1BF Wembley 2002-2007 Airline Reservation and ticketing

## Education

IHK Software Developer Certificate, January 2018 - January 2020 Training in Tokyo at ANA headquarters and at Haneda Airport. 2008 Japanese Language Proficiency Test 3 at SOAS University. 2007 Ticketing and fares training by Air France. 2005 "Frei" University, Berlin. Theatre Studies, Music and History of Art. 1995-1998 Humboldt University, Berlin (D). Translator and interpreter courses in German. 1993 VIII Technical College, Turin, Italy. Bachelor's Degree in Electronics. 1989